在上一集里
Previously on "Transformers Prime"...
你眼前的样本是在实验室中培养的
The specimen you see before you was bred in the laboratory
是由我在塞博特恩挖掘出的化石克隆而来
Cloned from fossilized remains, Which I discovered on Cybertron.
龙？虎子什么时候弄到了一条龙？
A dragon? Where'd the 'cons get a dragon?
通天晓？很荣幸见到您
Ultra Magnus? It's an honor.
要说 很荣幸见到您“长官”！
"it's an honor, sir."
我们必须阻止威震天 无论擎天柱在与不在
We must stop Megatron. With or without Optimus Prime.
是谁让这个垫肩男当家的？
Who put shoulderpads in command?
通天晓是唯一合乎逻辑的人选
Ultra Magnus is the only logical choice.
擎天柱 我拿到卓天越之锤了
Optimus! I have the forge!
它残余的能量必须用于复苏塞博特恩
Whatever power remains... must be used to restore Cybertron.
新领袖诞生的时刻已经到来！
The time for a new leader is upon us.
我坚信他此刻就站在我面前！
I believe that leader... stands before me right now.
汽车人们
Autobots.
目前我们在人数上仍然处于劣势 抛开弹药情况不谈
We remain vastly outnumbered, and, despite our munitions
我们也缺乏足够的火力去摧毁霸天虎的堡垒
Do not currently possess the firepower necessary to compromise the Decepticon citadel.
山姆大叔的军队倒是有足够的火力
Uncle sam's military does.
但我无权调动 否则威震天的巨炮会把华盛顿夷为平地
I just can't let them make a move as long as Megatron's ray guns are pointed at washington.
那么首先我们必须潜入黑山堡垒 摧毁那些融合加农炮
Then we must infiltrate darkmount, in order to nullify its fusion cannons.
不幸的是 那座堡垒屏蔽了所有未经授权的环陆桥出口
Unfortunately, it seems the fortress is heavily shielded against unauthorized groundbridges.
即使霸天虎自己的环陆桥技术也不例外
Even those originating from Decepticon technology.
看来我们得从敌人眼皮底下硬闯了
Guess we'll have to sneak past enemy lines.
以雷霆救援队的方式
Wrecker-style.
早在塞博特恩时 我就难以接受你们的行为
I couldn't deal with "wrecker-style" back on Cybertron
所以现在我仍不会批准
and I refuse to deal with it here.
哼
Hmm.
我们需要尽可能地将霸天虎调离老巢 以增加胜算
Now, we require a means of thinning the Decepticon ranks to even the odds
只有这样才有希望完成这次任务
If we're to have any hope of completing this mission...
或者说 幸存下来
or of surviving it.
我…我做不到
I-I can't do this.
我是说 没错 谁不想当领袖呢？
I mean, sure, who wouldn't wanna be a prime?
但我真的还没有做好准备 去承担那种责任
But I'm really not ready for that kind of responsibility.
烟幕…
Smokescreen...
你无权作出选择 我也一样…
The choice is neither yours, nor mine to make.
当时机到来时…
When it is time...
领导模块会在它所认可的火种面前现身
The matrix of leadership will present itself only to one whose spark is worthy.
这个方法上次效果不错
Because it worked so well last time...
我就知道人类控制不住使用移动通讯设备的欲望
I knew the humans couldn't resist using their telecommunications.
他们似乎干什么都离不开它
That is all they seem to do.
找到他 加以消灭
Seek and destroy!
有五个虎子正向杰克的位置集结
I have five bogeys converging right on top of jack.
不再是了
Not anymore.
神子 该你出场了
Miko, your turn.
你好 我要两个大号披萨
Hello, I need two large pies
西西里口味
Sicilian.
你们能送餐吧？
You deliver, right?
哼哼 人类啊
Hm hm ha ha ha... Humans.
准备环陆桥
Standby to groundbridge.
声波
Soundwave
当你人品爆发时 咋就无法接受它呢？
why can't you accept a little good fortune?
汽车人不可能永远跟我们躲猫猫
The Autobots couldn't possibly stay hidden forever.
我真的很想吃那个披萨
I really could have used that pizza.
我已经接入霸天虎的通讯网络了
I've tapped into the Decepticon communications network.
杰克 你准备好了吗？
Are you ready, Jack?
咳咳 霸天虎指挥中心 收到请回答？
Decepticon command, do you read me?
我觉得还不够逼真
I remain unconvinced.
我会用静电伪装 使其以假乱真
I will enhance your performance with static.
霸天虎指挥中心 请回答 我们正遭受汽车人的进攻！
Decepticon command, do you read? We are under autobot attack!
那里是我们的能量矿！
It's one of our energon mines!
机器昆虫 做好战斗准备！
Insecticons, prepare for battle!
汽车人们 子弹上膛！
Autobots, lock and load!
把引擎都给我开着 小伙子们
Keep your engines warm, boys.
一旦我们接到通天晓的信号 就立即出发！
We launch the moment Ultra Magnus gives the all-clear.
红蜘蛛指挥官 信息有误
There must be some mistake, commander Starscream.
矿工们并未遭受攻击
The mine is not under attack.
- 什么？怎么可能？\N- 红蜘蛛！
What? How can that--? Starscream!
解释一下为什么我的军队目前散落在全球各地？
Explain why my forces are scattering across this globe.
是那些该死的汽车人搞的鬼 威震天陛下
Uh, renegade Autobot mischief, lord Megatron!
我仍在分析他们是如何侵入我们的通讯系统\N却没有触发…
I am in the process of deducing how they are infiltrating our communications systems without the base of--
先驱号！
The Harbinger!
你竟把一艘能正常运行的霸天虎飞船\N丢在那里不管不顾？
You left abandoned Decepticon technology fully operational and unsecured?
呃…请允许我 立即去弥补自己的疏忽
Allow me to correct my oversight immediately.
追踪者部队到飞行甲板集合
Seeker armada to the flight deck.
（Seeker 追踪者 G1里是霸天虎喷气机部队的统称 近代作品中泛指霸天虎的空中部队）
Your target is the Decepticon ship, the Harbinger.
你们的目标是霸天虎飞船――先驱号
立即去把它轰成渣！
You are to obliterate it, at once!
我的大军已经就位
My armada is in position.
打开通向先驱号的环陆桥
Open a groundbridge to the Harbinger.
看来黑山堡垒目前正遭受攻击
Since it would seem that darkmount is under attack
调集所有留守力量 消灭入侵者
kindly redirect all efforts toward ensuring that our invaders our eradicated!
再吃我一颗！
Fire in another hole!
我向您保证 我的主人
I assure you, master
一切都在我的掌控之中
I have everything under control.
威震天陛下
Lord Megatron.
我承认军事行动并非我的专长
I accept that military considerations are outside of my domain
但似乎再次释放巨狰狞的时机已到
But perhaps it is once again time... to release the Predacon.
救护车 动手！
Ratchet, now!
这下可好
Oh, well...
对 去吧 找个没人的地方生闷气吧
Yes, that's right. Go off and sulk, why don't you?
是谁站在我的面前？
Who stands before me?
什么？是我啊 擎天柱
What? It's me, Optimus.
我是烟幕
Smokescreen.
谁…在召唤我…
Who... beckons...?
来吧 擎天柱
Come, Optimus.
真的是您吗？
Is it truly you...
钛师傅
Alpha Trion?
既然我出现在你面前 我的高徒
I stand before you, my student.
说明你的大限将至
As such, it would seem that it is your time.
你为何有所犹豫？
Why do you hesitate?
我并非畏惧回归火种源
I do not fear joining with the allspark
但是…我担忧领导模块的归属
but for the fate of the matrix of leadership.
你我都了然于心 一位优秀的人选就在眼前
You know as well as I, a worthy candidate is near.
他会成长为一名合格的领袖 就像当初的你一样
One who will learn to be a prime, as you once did.
通天晓呼叫突击小队
Ultra Magnus to stealth team.
汇报目前状况
Status report.
任务轻微受阻
Having a little trouble reaching the objective.
守卫比预想的要多 长官！
Security is tighter than anticipated, sir.
继续拖住他们！
Keep them occupied.
通天晓
Ultra Magnus.
让我猜猜 你想毁掉融合炮的能量核心 使其瘫痪
Allow me to venture: You intend to disarm my fusion cannons by disabling their power core.
没错 威震天
Indeed, Megatron
而你正挡在我的路上
and you are standing in my way.
你们的行动毫无逻辑可言
Your mission was most illogical.
糟糕！
Scrap.
通天晓…
Ultra Magnus.
你毕竟不是擎天柱
You are no Optimus Prime.
看在保罗・里维尔坐骑的份儿上 怎么这么久还没消息？
What in the name of Paul Revere's Horse is taking them so long?
（Paul Revere 保罗・里维尔 美国革命战争中因策马狂奔传递警报而闻名）
所有入侵者都已被捕 主人
All invaders have been taken captive, master.
但并没有发现擎天柱的踪迹
There was no sign of Optimus Prime.
那么 告诉我 指挥官
So tell me, commander...
你们的首领到底在哪儿？
Where might your leader be?
握紧我的手 擎天柱 与我重聚
Take my hand, Optimus, and join me.
回归火种源吧
Join with the allspark.
擎天柱 不！
Optimus, no!
故事不该以这种结局收场
This isn't how the story's supposed to end.
我不会再问第二遍
I will not ask again!
即使我知道 也不会告诉你
If I knew, I wouldn't tell you.
很好
Very well.
处死所有的俘虏 启动融合炮攻击射程内最近的大型城市
Execute our prisoners, and fire each cannon at the nearest metropolis within its sites.
我要让整个宇宙知道 这颗星球是属于我威震天的
It is time to show the known universe that this planet belongs to Megatron.
主人 有不明物体接近
Master, something's coming!
巨狰狞？
Predacon?
嗯…长得没那么邪乎
Hm... not beasty enough.
这怎么可能？
How is that possible?
什么？
What?
一个汽车人信号 但却是个飞行单位？
An Autobot signal. But it's airborne.
我认识那个涂装
I know that color scheme.
等等！他不会飞啊 难道不是吗？
Wait! He can't fly! Can he?
指挥官？
Commander?
长官 您看起来…强壮无比
Sir, you're looking... robust.
我们的当务之急是瘫痪下面的融合加农炮
It is paramount that we disable the fusion cannons below.
明白了
Understood.
全员注意 擎天柱回归了
All units... Optimus Prime has returned.
- 太棒了！\N- 好极了！\N- 感谢火种源！
- Yes!\N- Awesome!\N- Thank the allspark!\N- Sweet!
我重复一遍 擎天柱还活着 并且状态极佳
I repeat, Prime is alive and quite well.
好哎！
Yes!
擎――天――柱！！！
Optimus!
指挥官 大量敌对信号迫近！
Commander, a cluster of enemy signals, incoming!
哼 人类！
Ah! Humans.
启动融合加农炮！
Activate the fusion cannons!
空中霸王战机 等待我的指令
Sky Strikers, await my command.
（Sky Striker 空中霸王 孩之宝旗下\N另一品牌G.I.Joe里面特种部队方面的主力战机）
威――震――天！
Megatron
给我消失吧！
begone!
汽车人们 撤离该地区
Autobots, clear the area.
动手吧！
Let's do this.
声波 请求开启环陆桥
Soundwave, I require a groundbridge.
把威震天陛下转移到战舰上去
Transport lord Megatron to the warship.
你在干什么！
What are you doing?
不！我们绝不撤退！
No! We will not retreat!
我们已经输掉了这场战斗 我的君王
This battle is lost, my liege.
如果我们还想有翻盘的机会 现在必须撤退！
We must retreat if we are to have any hope of winning the war.
啊！我错过正戏了！
Aw, I missed it!
我谨代表美国总统和美军联合参谋本部
On behalf of the president and the joint chiefs
感谢你们在守卫这颗星球时所表现出的大无畏精神
I thank you all for your selfless heroism in defense of this planet.
非常遗憾 你们的杰出贡献仍无法被公诸于世
I'm sorry the world can't know of your undying dedication
但对我个人来说 我欠你们一条命 一份自由 还有一个未来
because I, for one, owe you my life, my liberty, and my future.
长官 我非常荣幸地将汽车人的指挥权交还给您
Sir, I am honored to relinquish command of the Autobots to you.
欢迎来到地球 通天晓
Welcome to earth, Ultra Magnus.
也欢迎你加入领袖卫队
And to team prime.
好吧 这句话我憋了好久了
Okay, someone's gotta say it.
擎天柱2.0版酷毙了！
Optimus 2.0 is rad!
想想卓天越之锤可以把你们改成什么样
Imagine what the forge could do for your bod.
卓天越之锤的能量真的完全耗尽了吗？
Is it true that the forge has been drained of its power?
那么重铸终极之锁已经彻底无望了
Then any hope of rebuilding the Omega Lock has truly been lost.
我…我做了自己认为对的事
I did what I felt was right.
那么你再次证明了你的直觉是正确的
And your instincts have again proven to be quite sound.
耶！
Yeah!